Mohammed Jameem

Kerala, India • +91-9809 832 461

jameemkurikkal.mp@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/jameem/ • https://github.com/Jameem

(Open for relocating to EUROPE)

Backend Developer | Full-Stack Javascript Developer | Project Team Lead

Senior Software Developer having seven years of experience in web development in different languages and platforms, can handle challenging situations and competitive environments. Passionate programmer and a self learner who is very enthusiastic about new technologies. Lead developer for software development and deployment with my current employer.

CORE COMPETENCIES & ACHIEVEMENTS

Full-Stack Web Development | Agile Project Management | Devops

- Extensive experience in web development. Seven years of experience facilitating cutting-edge engineering solutions with a wide range of web application and technology skills.
- **Full-stack web development.** Proven ability to leverage full-stack expertise to build interactive and scalable web applications.
- Experienced NodeJs, ReactJS developer. Experienced in developing web applications using Node.js, Express.js, React JS, Redux, Postgresql, MongoDB etc.
- Experience in Devops. Worked with Docker, Travis CI and AWS for the production deployment.
- Experience in PHP Laravel. Used PHP Laravel and MySql in various projects as per the requirements.
- **Team player** with a can-do attitude with ability to work in a fast paced environment.
- **Time Management**. Phenomenal time management skills, and a strong user focus.
- **Passionate** programmer and an advocate for people-first, collaborative company culture, constant learning and open-source tools.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS & KNOWLEDGE

JavaScript | NodeJS | ReactJS | Postgresql

- Programming Languages: Javascript, Php, C#, Solidity.
- Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Rest.
- JavaScript Libraries: Node.js, React.js, Express.js, Mocha.
- Data Management: Postgresql, MySQL, MSSQL, MongoDB.
- Devops: Docker, Travis CI, AWS
- Project Management: Agile, Scrum, Waterfall.
- Blockchain Development: Ethereum, Smart Contracts.
- Code Versioning: Git

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Project Team Lead Qubicle Innovations Pvt. Ltd

September 2019 - Present

- Leading the development of Enterprise Resource Planning applications.
- Integrated modules such as Inventory Sales, Purchase, Manufacturing, Accounts, Banking and HRM.
- Working on an ERP application focused on manufacturing for Qatar Steel Foundation.
- Working on an ERP application for Middle East Building Material & Co.
- Migrated the applications to AWS cloud.
- Technology Stack: NodeJS, PostgreSql, ReactJS, Redux and AWS.

Full-Stack Developer Premier Logistics LLC

July 2017 - August 2019

- Integral part of a team that handled the software development life cycle for various industry specific applications, end to end.
- Structured several internal systems comprising order entry/management tools, conversion/revenue reporting and production workflow tracking, as well as designed custom REST APIs built in NodeJS and PHP Laravel.
- Built a search application for warehouses where users can search and find warehouses as per his criteria.
- Built an asset management application for one of the biggest companies in Dubai.
- Built different industry specific applications such as warehouse management, cargo shipping portal, warehouse search engine, asset management, property management etc.
- Used NodeJs & PHP Laravel on the server side with MongoDB & MySQL as the database and ReactJs on the front-end as per the requirements of the project.
- Technology Stack: Php Laravel, NodeJS, ReactJS, MySQL, MongoDB

June 2014 - June 2017

Web Developer Codinoz Technologies

- Designed and implemented PHP web applications, streamlining high-server traffic resource configuration and allocation.
- Successfully generated back-end programming utilizing LAMP stack; Linux, Apache, PHP 5, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery, and MySQL frameworks.
- Developed, implemented and maintained ERP applications as per the requirements of the client.
 Collaborated with technical and business staff in the design, development, testing, implementation and production support of enterprise applications.
- Used PHP and Asp.net on the back-end, MySQL & SQLServer as the database and pure HTML and JavaScript on the front-end.

Junior Web Developer Polosys Technologies LLP

- Built online and offline business applications in C# and Asp.net with HTML and Javascript on the front-end and SQLServer as the database.
- Implemented new C# class library for the SQL server database access layer, and updated previous web page frameworks.
- Developed an application which will manage day to day businesses for one of biggest fruit exporters of the state which was the first successful project of my career.
- Took part in various online and offline business applications according to the requirements.

EDUCATION

University of Calicut, India
 Bachelor of Technology(2009 – 2013)

CERTIFICATIONS

- CERTIFIED BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER (ETHEREUM)
 Provided by Blockchain Training Alliance in association with Pearson-vue
- IBM BLOCKCHAIN FOUNDATION DEVELOPER
- IBM BLOCKCHAIN ESSENTIALS